wowzio.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Wowzio

Wowzio has established this privacy policy to explain to you, our users, how your information is protected, collected and used, which may be updated by Wowzio from time to time. Wowzio will provide notice of materially significant changes to this privacy policy by posting notice on the Wowzio site. 

Protecting your privacy

We don't share your personally identifiable information with third parties for marketing purposes. We don't send you unsolicited communications for marketing purposes. We do not post your email anywhere on our site, to help prevent 3rd party harvesting and spam. Please make sure that you do not post your email or any other contact information in your profile. Account information is password-protected. Keep your password safe. Wowzio, or people who post on Wowzio, may provide links to third party websites, which may have different privacy practices. We are not responsible for, nor have any control over, the privacy policies of those third party websites, and encourage all users to read the privacy policies of each and every website visited. 

Data we collect

We collect your email address for one or more purposes like registration & login, sending self-publishing and confirmation emails, authenticating user accounts, invites, providing subscription email services, feedback, etc. We may collect personal information if you provide it in profile, registration, feedback or comments, post it on our interactive forums, or if you contact us directly. Please do not post or provide any personal information on Wowzio's that you expect to keep private. We may also collect data based on users' usage of the site and its various features like widgets and badges, but it is not personally identifiable except as described below under the IP Addresses section ("Aggregate Data"). In addition, we may take your personal information and create anonymized information by excluding information that makes it personally identifiable to you ("Anonymized Data"). 

IP Addresses ( Aggregate Data )

We compile logs of IP addresses of users of the site & its services for administrative and analytical purposes. We also cache IP addresses of users for a short period of time to power some features on our site ( geo-popularity ) as well as our widgets ( live activity widget ). We do not routinely collect any personally identifiable information through our compilation of IP addresses. However, in cases of suspected abuse or service problems, we may use an IP address in conjunction with other personally identifiable information to enforce our terms of use and/or to protect or troubleshoot the site, its users or others who may be affected. Except as provided in "Use & Share of Data we collect" we will not share personally identifiable information associated with IP addresses with third parties. 

Data collected by 3rd parties

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Specifically, we use Google as an Ad provider, which uses cookies to serve ads on Wowzio. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to Wowzio and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

This privacy policy does not apply to information collected by advertisers, vendors or other third parties whose content, ads or promotions appear on our website but who operate independently of this site. It is advised that readers first check the individual privacy policies of such third parties before providing personal information. 

Data we store

We store blog posts as well as thumbnails of images in blog posts, to present and publish them in our widgets. If you are a blog owner, and would like us to stop doing this, please send us an email, clearly identifying yourself to info [at] wowzio [dot] com. Once we have verified ownership of the blog, we will deactivate all widgets related to your blog, and stop further distribution of your blog's content. All feedback is stored in our database, and feedback records are purged/deleted from time to time. Our web logs are currently stored for just the past few days. 

Use & Share of Data we collect

We use the data we collect from our users in the following manner: 

  * to help us improve our content and services
  * to allow readers to participate in site-related activities and events
  * to show advertising and content that we think may be of interest to a particular user
  * to enforce our terms of service 
  * to send mailings

We may share Aggregated Data and Anonymized Data with third parties. 

We will not provide your Personal Information to a third party in the absence of your express approval, except as follows: 

  * With trusted third party service providers who help us in the operation of our business and who have agreed to maintain the confidentiality of the data 
  * In cases of abusive behavior or suspected violations of our terms of use in order to investigate the violation and to take appropriate action 
  * Where we have a good faith belief that it is required in order to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, to prevent fraud or imminent harm, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims 
  * If this site is sold or transferred to another company, your Personal Information will also be transferred and you will be notified. 

Archiving and display of Wowzio pages by search engines and other sites

Search engines and other sites not affiliated with Wowzio - including [archive.org](http://archive.org/), [google.com](http://www.google.com/), and [search.yahoo.com](http://search.yahoo.com/) \- archive or otherwise make available Wowzio's pages and content. 

Circumstances in which Wowzio may release information

Wowzio may disclose information about its users if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. Wowzio may also disclose information about its users to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, respond to claims that any posting or other content violates the rights of third-parties; or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Wowzio, its users or the general public. 

International Users

By visiting our web site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that due to the international dimension of Wowzio we may use the data collected in the course of our relationship for the purposes identified in this policy or in our other communications with you, including the transmission of information outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, please understand that such data may be stored on servers located in the United States. By providing us with your data, you consent to the transfer of such data. 

Feedback

We welcome your feedback on this document on our feedback page.
